Hello English learners, welcome back to another lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
各位英语学习者好，欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的又一堂课。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是 Erika。
And today we're going to be talking about physics.
今天我们要讨论物理学。
That's right.
没错。
An advanced lesson for all you physics lovers out there.
这是一节高级课程，献给所有热爱物理学的朋友们。
And even for those of you who maybe don't love physics so much, there's still some great
即使你们中有些人可能不太喜欢物理，
language here.
这里面也有一些很棒的语言点。
Right.
对。
We're going to be talking about the Big Bang Theory, a very popular theory of how the universe
我们要讨论的是大爆炸理论，这是一个非常流行的理论，关于宇宙
or the world and how we came upon being created.
或世界以及我们是如何被创造出来的。
That's right.
没错。
So we've got some physics language, but we've also got some really tough words that I bet
所以我们会涉及一些物理术语，但也有一些非常难的词汇，我敢打赌
many of our users have never seen before, which we're going to look at those in this
很多用户以前从未见过，我们会在本节课中
lesson.
学习这些词。
All right.
好的。
So why don't we get started with this great and interesting lesson.
那我们开始这堂精彩又有趣的课吧。
And let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
让我们第一次听对话。
What's up?
怎么了？
You don't look too good.
你看起来不太好。
Yeah, my head hurts.
是啊，我头疼。
That's all.
就这些。
I've been in physics class all day.
我上了一整天的物理课。
It's killer.
太折磨人了。
I liked physics.
我以前喜欢物理。
It's all math really.
其实全是数学。
Arcs, curves, velocity, cool stuff.
弧线、曲线、速度，很酷的东西。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
But today's lesson was all about the creation of the universe.
但今天的课全是关于宇宙的创造。
A physics class about the creation of the universe?
一堂关于宇宙创造的物理课？
That's some pretty unscientific language there.
这语言听起来很不科学啊。
It sounds more religious to me.
对我来说更像宗教。
It's all religion.
全是宗教。
Take the theory of the Big Bang.
就拿大爆炸理论来说吧。
How is it possible that all of the stuff in the universe comes from an explosion?
宇宙中所有的东西怎么可能来自一场爆炸？
That's no better than Atlas carrying the globe on his back or African myths about turtles
这并不比阿特拉斯背着地球，或者非洲神话里关于乌龟
and stuff.
之类的说法好多少。
Turtles?
乌龟？
Whatever.
随便吧。
Look, all that's required for the creation of matter is an imbalance of particles and
听着，创造物质所需要的只是粒子和
antiparticles.
反粒子的不平衡。
At least that's what the math says.
至少数学是这么说的。
Math?
数学？
Schmath.
算了吧。
What's the evidence?
证据呢？
There is evidence.
有证据。
You know Edwin Hubble, the guy who in the early 20th century was the first scientist
你知道埃德温·哈勃吧，他在20世纪初是第一位
to measure the drift of matter in the universe, thus advancing notions of an expanding universe.
测量宇宙中物质漂移的科学家，从而推进了宇宙膨胀的概念。
What would it be expanding from?
它是从什么开始膨胀的？
Well, the Big Bang, duh.
嗯，大爆炸啊，这还用说。
Anyway, it's just a theory.
不管怎样，它只是一个理论。
Why do people go around touting theories?
为什么人们到处吹捧理论？
Where's the rigor in that?
严谨性在哪里？
Dude, don't equivocate.
老兄，别含糊其辞。
A theory only becomes a theory after withstanding rigorous testing.
一个理论只有在经受住严格测试之后才能成为理论。
You slept through class, didn't you?
你上课睡着了，对吧？
You're making my head hurt again.
你又让我头疼了。
Quit with the questions.
别问问题了。
Well it sure does sound like a difficult class, doesn't it?
这听起来确实像一门很难的课，对吧？
It's a very interesting topic and very controversial, so there are many opinions on it.
这是一个非常有趣且非常有争议的话题，所以有很多观点。
But before we get into that, why don't we take a look at some of those physics-related
但在我们深入讨论之前，不如先看看在“语言要点”环节中
words that we listen to in Language Takeaway.
听到的一些与物理相关的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
We've got four words we've heard in the dialogue that are all related to physics.
我们在对话中听到了四个与物理相关的词。
So let's start with the first one, which is matter.
我们先从第一个开始，那就是“物质”。
Matter.
物质。
Okay, so you probably know this word from what's the matter, what's wrong.
好的，你可能从“怎么了”这个短语中认识这个词。
In this case, we're talking about matter, so anything that occupies space, that has
在这里，我们讨论的是物质，也就是任何占据空间、
a mass or that is related to energy.
有质量或与能量相关的东西。
So matter.
所以是物质。
So all things in the world are made up of matter, right?
所以世界上所有东西都是由物质构成的，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Now let's move on to another one.
现在我们来看下一个。
Particles.
粒子。
Now particles are a little bit more, now particles are a little bit easier.
粒子稍微……粒子稍微容易理解一些。
They're just very small pieces of a whole.
它们只是整体的非常小的部分。
An apple is made up of apple particles?
一个苹果是由苹果粒子组成的？
Something like that.
差不多吧。
If you want to understand it easily, yeah, apple has many small particles that make up
如果你想简单理解，是的，苹果由许多小粒子组成，
the apple.
构成了苹果。
So like, let's paint a picture here.
我们来描绘一下。
Imagine you've got a beach and all the pieces of sand are particles of the beach.
想象你有一个海滩，所有的沙粒都是海滩的粒子。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So those are particles.
所以那些就是粒子。
Now the next one is a little bit difficult for me.
下一个对我来说有点难。
I don't understand this.
我不太懂这个。
Antiparticles.
反粒子。
All right.
好的。
So antiparticles.
所以是反粒子。
Antiparticles.
反粒子。
Now this prefix, anti, it means something that is against, right?
这个前缀“反”表示反对的意思，对吧？
Right.
对。
I've seen this one in anti-clockwise.
我在“逆时针”这个词里见过这个。
All right.
好的。
So antiparticles are those that are against particles.
所以反粒子就是与粒子相对的那些。
So basically if you have a particle that has a positive charge and another one comes in
基本上，如果你有一个带正电荷的粒子，另一个
with a negative charge in the same weight and the same type of particle, if they get
带负电荷、相同重量和类型的粒子过来，
together, they cancel each other out and they both die.
如果它们碰到一起，就会相互抵消，然后都消失。
So that's an antiparticle.
这就是反粒子。
All right.
好的。
Well, you heard it first.
嗯，你第一次听到这个。
You're at English Pod.
你在 EnglishPod。
So antiparticles are not a good thing to have around.
所以反粒子不是什么好东西。
Now we also heard them talk about the drift of matter.
我们还听到他们谈论物质的漂移。
Right.
对。
Drift of matter.
物质的漂移。
Also sometimes called drift of dark matter.
有时也叫暗物质的漂移。
Okay.
好的。
Well, I know the verb to drift, right?
嗯，我知道动词“漂移”，对吧？
To sort of float away on the sea.
就是像在海上慢慢漂走。
Right.
对。
If you have a little ship, you leave it on the beach, it'll drift away.
如果你有一艘小船，把它留在海滩上，它会漂走。
It'll go slowly away.
它会慢慢漂走。
Yeah.
是的。
But what about drift of matter?
但物质的漂移呢？
So basically the drift of matter is this residue, the remains of the big bang, of the explosion.
基本上，物质的漂移就是大爆炸、爆炸后的残留物。
Okay.
好的。
So matter and radiation keeps on drifting through the universe.
所以物质和辐射一直在宇宙中漂移。
So it's moving slowly through the universe.
所以它在宇宙中缓慢移动。
Moving slowly.
缓慢移动。
So this big explosion and just consider it to be like this ripple and it's expanding
所以这次大爆炸，可以把它想象成涟漪，它正在
and expanding.
不断膨胀、膨胀。
That's the drift of matter.
那就是物质的漂移。
All right.
好的。
Well, I learned something else today.
嗯，我今天又学到了一些东西。
Some very specific words related to physics, but it's very interesting.
一些与物理相关的非常具体的词汇，但非常有趣。
Once you get into reading about these things, it will help you to understand it better.
一旦你开始阅读这些东西，它会帮助你更好地理解。
That's right.
没错。
But we've also got some non-physics related language that we want to look at now in Language
但我们还有一些与物理无关的语言点，我们想在“语言要点”
Takeaway part two.
第二部分中看看。
So they were talking about the drift of matter and how it's drifting through the universe.
他们谈论了物质的漂移以及它如何在宇宙中漂移。
And then he said, thus advancing the notions of an expanding universe.
然后他说，“从而推进了宇宙膨胀的概念”。
So I want to look at the phrase, thus advancing notions.
所以我想看看“从而推进概念”这个短语。
Thus advancing notions.
从而推进概念。
Okay.
好的。
Let's start with the first word here.
我们先从第一个词开始。
Thus.
从而。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a good connector.
这是一个很好的连接词。
Or conjunction.
或者连词。
And basically it means.
基本上它的意思是。
Therefore.
因此。
Therefore or in consequence.
因此或结果。
Right?
对吧？
So thus advancing notions.
所以“从而推进概念”。
Now notions are ideas.
现在“概念”就是想法。
Right.
对。
And so when you advance notions or advance ideas, you help them make progress.
所以当你推进概念或推进想法时，你帮助它们取得进展。
You help them go forward and become known.
你帮助它们前进并为人所知。
Okay.
好的。
So in order to understand this in the context, they are saying that the drift of matter thus
为了在上下文中理解这个，他们说的是物质的漂移从而
advances notions of an expanding universe.
推进了宇宙膨胀的概念。
So it is making progress to people believing that the universe is getting bigger.
所以它让人们逐渐相信宇宙正在变大。
Okay.
好的。
So interesting phrase.
很有趣的短语。
Now, I really like this word thus.
现在，我真的很喜欢“从而”这个词。
And a lot of people are afraid to use it.
很多人不敢用它。
So why don't we hear a few examples of how it's used in context.
所以我们来听几个它在语境中使用的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
So you can see that we've studied the fossil record and thus we can conclude that evolution
所以你可以看到，我们研究了化石记录，从而我们可以得出结论，进化
is a fact.
是一个事实。
Example two.
例子二。
He broke severe company policies.
他严重违反了公司政策。
Thus we had to fire him.
因此我们不得不解雇他。
Example three.
例子三。
I did not receive the documents on time.
我没有按时收到文件。
Thus I was unable to send them to you.
因此我无法把它们发给你。
All right.
好的。
Good examples of thus.
“从而”的好例子。
And I guess now we can use it a little bit better.
我想我们现在可以更好地使用它了。
That's right.
没错。
Now let's move on to our next word.
现在我们来看下一个词。
So they were talking about people who go around touting theories.
他们谈论了那些到处吹捧理论的人。
Tout.
吹捧。
To tout.
Okay.
好的。
So what does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Tout.
吹捧。
Well, basically when you tout something, you talk about it in a positive way.
嗯，基本上当你吹捧某样东西时，你以积极的方式谈论它。
So as to almost like sell that thing.
几乎就像在推销那样东西。
So for example, we can say the company is touting the many benefits of its product.
例如，我们可以说公司正在吹捧其产品的诸多好处。
Okay very good.
好的，非常好。
So to talk positively about something.
所以是积极谈论某样东西。
Yeah, with the idea of trying to sell that thing or make people buy into it or believe
是的，带着试图推销那样东西或让人们接受它或相信
it.
它的想法。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
What about our next word?
下一个词呢？
Well, we heard two related words in the dialogue.
嗯，我们在对话中听到了两个相关的词。
They were talking about where's the rigor in these theories and rigorous testing.
他们谈论了这些理论的严谨性在哪里，以及严格的测试。
Okay, so what's the difference between rigor and rigorous?
好的，那么“严谨”和“严格的”有什么区别？
Rigor is the state of being very clear and careful and exact.
“严谨”是一种非常清晰、仔细和精确的状态。
Okay.
好的。
And rigorous is just the adjective.
而“严格的”只是形容词形式。
Clear, careful, attention to detail and exact.
清晰、仔细、注重细节和精确。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So rigorous training.
所以是严格的训练。
I'm going over my notes in rigorous detail.
我正在以极其严谨的细节复习我的笔记。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And now we have one more word today in language takeaway and that is equivocate.
今天在“语言点”环节我们还有一个词，那就是“equivocate”。
So we heard dude, don't equivocate.
所以我们听到“老兄，别含糊其辞”。
Don't equivocate.
别含糊其辞。
All right.
好的。
So what does he mean by this?
那他这么说是什么意思呢？
Well, when you equivocate, you use big words to try and mislead somebody.
嗯，当你“equivocate”时，你用大词来试图误导别人。
Okay.
好的。
So using big words to confuse or to mislead.
所以是用大词来混淆或误导。
Yep.
是的。
So for example, we could say the job candidate, we could say when asked about his experience,
比如，我们可以说那个求职者，当被问及他的经验时，
the job candidate equivocated.
那个求职者含糊其辞。
Okay, or even the presidential nominee did not equivocate when he explained his tax policy.
好的，或者甚至可以说那位总统候选人在解释他的税收政策时没有含糊其辞。
All right.
好的。
So some good examples, good phrases, a lot of interesting stuff and a little bit more
所以有一些很好的例子、很好的短语，今天这期播客也多了点
educational podcast today.
教育意味。
That's right.
没错。
So let's continue with our education by listening to the dialogue one last time.
那让我们最后再听一遍对话，继续我们的学习吧。
What's up?
怎么了？
You don't look too good.
你看起来不太好。
Yeah, my head hurts.
是啊，我头疼。
That's all.
就这样。
I've been in physics class all day.
我上了一整天的物理课。
It's killer.
太要命了。
I liked physics.
我喜欢物理。
It's all math really.
其实全是数学。
Arcs, curves, velocity, cool stuff.
弧线、曲线、速度，很酷的东西。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
But today's lesson was all about the creation of the universe.
但今天的课全是关于宇宙的创造。
A physics class about the creation of the universe?
一堂关于宇宙创造的物理课？
That's some pretty unscientific language there.
那用语可太不科学了。
It sounds more religious to me.
对我来说听起来更像宗教。
It's all religion.
全是宗教。
Take the theory of the Big Bang.
就拿大爆炸理论来说。
How is it possible that all of the stuff in the universe comes from an explosion?
宇宙中所有的东西怎么可能来自一场爆炸？
That's no better than Atlas carrying the globe on his back or African myths about turtles
那不比阿特拉斯扛着地球，或者非洲神话里关于乌龟
and stuff.
之类的说法好多少。
Turtles?
乌龟？
Whatever.
随便啦。
Look, all that's required for the creation of matter is an imbalance of particles and
听着，创造物质所需要的只是粒子和反粒子的
antiparticles.
不平衡。
At least that's what the math says.
至少数学是这么说的。
Math?
数学？
Schmath!
数学个屁！
What's the evidence?
证据呢？
There is evidence.
有证据。
You know Edwin Hubble, the guy who in the early 20th century was the first scientist
你知道埃德温·哈勃吧，就是那个在20世纪初第一个
to measure the drift of matter in the universe, thus advancing notions of an expanding universe.
测量宇宙中物质漂移，从而推动了宇宙膨胀概念的科学家。
What would it be expanding from?
它从什么开始膨胀？
Well, the Big Bang, duh.
嗯，大爆炸啊，废话。
Anyway, it's just a theory.
反正，它只是个理论。
Why do people go around touting theories?
为什么人们到处吹捧理论？
Where's the rigor in that?
那里面哪有什么严谨性？
Dude, don't equivocate.
老兄，别含糊其辞。
A theory only becomes a theory after withstanding rigorous testing.
一个理论只有在经受住严格检验之后才能成为理论。
You slept through class, didn't you?
你上课睡过去了，是吧？
You're making my head hurt again.
你又让我头疼了。
Quit with the questions.
别问问题了。
Alright, so the Big Bang theory, very controversial.
好了，所以大爆炸理论，非常有争议。
In some schools in the United States, they have prohibited the teachers from teaching
在美国的一些学校，他们禁止老师教授
it.
它。
I know, which seems quite interesting to me.
我知道，这对我来说挺有意思的。
But it is actually very controversial and people can get really, really upset about
但这在美国确实非常有争议，人们可能会对此非常非常
this in America.
恼火。
So it is an interesting topic.
所以这是个有趣的话题。
Take it from the point of view of just something else, maybe just to learn a little bit more
从另一个角度来看，也许只是为了多学一点关于这个主题的东西，比如物理，对吧？
about this topic such as physics, right?
对。
Right.
But there's something that is uncontroversial that I did want to talk about now that we
但有一件事是没有争议的，我现在想谈谈我们在对话中
heard in the dialogue.
听到的。
There's a lot of really interesting sort of slang words here in the dialogue, isn't
对话里有很多非常有趣的俚语词，是不是？
there?
是不是？
We heard it in the first part of the dialogue when he said, I've been in physics class all
我们在对话的第一部分听到他说“我上了一整天的物理课”。
day.
我上了一整天的物理课。
Killer.
要命。
So what does he mean by killer?
那他说的“要命”是什么意思？
Oh, he's just basically saying it's really hard.
哦，他基本上就是说这很难。
You know, it's like it's so difficult that it's murderous.
你知道，就是难到要命。
It was intense.
很激烈。
Yeah.
是啊。
But this word we can use positively as well, can't we?
但这个词我们也可以正面使用，对吧？
Yeah, I guess you could say that was a killer party.
是啊，我想你可以说那是个超棒的派对。
Yeah, killer moves on the dance floor.
是啊，舞池里动作超酷。
Okay.
好的。
Another interesting thing is that he said math schmath.
另一件有趣的事是他说了“数学个屁”。
Now schmath isn't really a word.
现在“个屁”其实不是个词。
No, but this is a really common structure we use in English when we want to sort of
不，但这是英语中一个非常常见的结构，当我们想
take away from the importance of an idea.
削弱一个想法的重要性时使用。
Okay.
好的。
So you're saying it's not important.
所以你是说它不重要。
I don't care about it or it's not worth it.
我不在乎它，或者它不值得。
Yeah.
是啊。
So for example, I'm on a diet.
比如，我在节食。
Right.
对。
And I would say diet schmath.
我会说“节食个屁”。
Yeah.
是啊。
So basically the structure is just added sh and then just kind of make it rhyme.
所以基本上这个结构就是加个“sh”然后让它押韵。
Yeah.
是啊。
Schmath or like.
就像“数学个屁”或者。
Like work schmirk.
比如“工作个屁”。
Yeah.
是啊。
Work schmirk or something like that.
“工作个屁”之类的。
Yeah.
是啊。
So you're making fun of it and you're taking away importance.
所以你在嘲笑它并削弱它的重要性。
Yeah.
是啊。
That's a pretty neat phrase.
那是个很妙的短语。
And one more.
还有一个。
We heard them say duh.
我们听到他们说“废话”。
Duh.
废话。
So when we say this, we're just saying like, you should know this, stupid.
当我们这么说的时候，我们就是说“你应该知道这个，笨蛋”。
Yeah.
是啊。
This is obvious.
这很明显。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's kind of making fun of the person or just saying it's so obvious, how can you not know
有点在嘲笑那个人，或者说这太明显了，你怎么可能不知道
it?
呢？
Yeah.
是啊。
And it always goes either at the beginning or at the end of a sentence.
而且它总是在句子的开头或结尾。
Yeah.
是啊。
So duh, Marco, we're recording a podcast.
所以“废话，Marco，我们在录播客呢”。
Right.
对。
Very good.
非常好。
So some great words and phrases in this dialogue and a little bit of slang as well so you can
所以这个对话里有一些很棒的词和短语，还有一些俚语，这样你就可以
use it maybe with your friends.
也许和你的朋友一起用。
That's right.
没错。
If you have any questions about the language in this dialogue or any thoughts on physics
如果你对这个对话中的语言有任何疑问，或者对物理
or the Big Bang Theory, come and check out our website at EnglishPod.com.
或大爆炸理论有任何想法，欢迎访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there and until next time.
我们会在那里等你们，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Take care, guys.
保重，各位。